Mss.B.P31
American Philosophical Society
- Series 3: Legal and Financial Records, 1705-1856; 4 boxes, 2 linear feet
  - Account with Alfred Skinner, July 9, 1812 - May 27, 1813; 5-3/4x7-3/4; Cooley, William
  - Certification that Charles L[innaeus] Peale has fought, Jan. 17, 1815; 6x7-1/4; Habacker, William
    D.S.: William Habacker and George Shubert 1p. vol. VIp.58
  - Account with Abial A. Colley, administrator, Sept. 8, 1815 -Jan. 25, 1817; 7-1/4x8; Cooley, Samuel. Estate
  - Inventory, Oct. 2, 1815; 12x7-1/4; Cooley, Samuel. Estate
    Bolton, D.S.: Joseph Carver and Duthan Avery. 1p.and end.
  - Sale, Oct. 2, 1815; 11x7; Cooley, Samuel. Estate
    D.S.: Abiah H. Cooley. 1p.and end.
  - Petition to the city commissioners of Philadelphia for tax exemption for his museum, [1815?]; 9x7-1/4; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    A.D. 10p. Refers to Rittenhouse, J.Vaughan and Sir Joseph Banks.
  - Certificate for one share of stock issued to Charles Caldwall, Jan. 1, 1816; 8" x 5 1/2"; Athenaeum of Philadelphia
    Phila., Printed D. S: Roberts Vaux, treasurer. 1p. and end. On the reverse, Dr. Caldwell transfers the share to Reubens [Peale]; Oct. 8, 1819. Mutilated.
  - Receipt to John Sellers for Schooling for Abigal Goore, April 8, 1816; 3x8; Rhoads, Hannah, 1793-1865
    D.S. 1p. vol I p.89
  - Settlement of creditors claims, Aug. 20, 1816; 13x8; Cooley, Samuel. Estate
    Bolton D.S.: Joseph Carver and Duthan Avery. 1p.and end.
  - Statement of account with Charles Willson Peale, April, 1816 and 1817; 4-1/2x8; Fitzsimmons, Charles
    D. 1p. vol VII p. 8
  - Memorial to the Select and Common Councils of Philadelphia begging them to accept the proposal made by C.W. Peale relative to his museum, [1816]; Philadelphia. Citizens
    Photostat of D.S.: W[illia]m Tilghman and 25 others. 3p.
  - Concerning Benjamin Howard's will, Jan. 20, 1817; 8-1/2x7-3/4; Ruggles, John, 1789-1874
    Bolton, D.S.: John Ruggles, Ebenezer Strong and Oliver Webster. 1p.and end. vol. I p.57
  - Memorandum for Charles Willson Peale concerning the settling of William and Christiana De Peyster's estates with Remsen, [1818]; 10x8 and 13x7-3/4; De Peyster, Philip, 1771-1846
    D. 3p. and memorandum by C.W.Peale on same subject.
  - Oath of originality for patent, July 21, 1820; 10x8; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    D.S. 1p.and end.
  - Specification of an invention for a patent, July 21, 1820; 12-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    A.D.S.: Nn.and Dd.Sellers. 2p.,end.
  - Warrant for the arrest of Anthony and Elizabeth Loop, Dec. 6, 1820; 4-1/4x8-1/4; Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, Printed D. filled in in ms.S.: Robert Wharton, Mayor. 1p.
  - Deed to Coleman Sellers, 1820; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Sontag, Hannah
    Draft of D. 2p.
  - An act to incorporate the Philadelphia Museum, Feb. 1, 1821; 15-1/2x10; Pennsylvania. Laws, statutes, etc.
    D.S.: Joseph Hiester, Gov. 4p. and 1p. printed D.filled in in ms.S.: Joseph Hiester, Gov.
  - Petition to the select council of Philadelphia, April 11, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Peale's Museum (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Philadelphia, D.S.: R.Patterson, Zaccheus Collins, Coleman Sellers, Rubens Peale. 2p.and end. Asks for more room in state house. vol VII p. 20
  - Minutes, April 13, 1821; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Philadelphia. Select council
    D.S.: Thomas Bradford. 1p.and add.: William Meredith. Concerning the state house and the museum.
  - Receipt to Ann Sellers, May 28, 1821; 4-1/2x8; Sharpless, Townsend, b. 1793
    A.D.S. 1p.and end. vol I,p.97
  - Lease to the Philadelphia Museum Co., Oct. 21, 1821; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Philadelphia. City commissioners
    D.S.: Jos[eph] Morris, Thomas T. Stiles, Nathan Atherbury, Rob[er]t H. Smith, and Michael McCloskey. 4p.,end. Copy. Lease of Independence Hall. vol. VII p.22
  - Quarterly report of the manager, Sept. 30, 1822; 10x15-1/2; Peale's Museum (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Philadelphia, D.S.: C.W.Peale. Examined: C. Sellers. 1p.and end. (see Peale Papers. Mills collection.)
  - Stock inventory, Jan. 1, 1823 - Jan. 1, 1824; 13-1/2x8; Sellers, Nathan & David
  - Petition to Governor [of Pennsylvania] John Andrew Shulze, [1823?]; 13-1/4x8-1/4; Peale, Charles Linneaus, 1794-1832
    D. 1p. Asks for position.
  - Warrant for the arrest of John Witner, Jan. 1, 1824; 6-1/2x8; Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, Printed D.filled in in ms. S.: Robert Wharton, Mayor. 1p.and end.
    Note by H.W. Sellers: "Old papers found in the attic of Congress Hall, 6th and Chestnut Streets, during the restoration of the building."
  - Minutes, Aug. 23, 1824; 12-1/2x7-3/4; The American Democracy
    D.S.: Jonathan Sourman, chairman and Cha[rle]s L[innaeus] Peale, Secretary. 2p. Resolution for election of Andrew Jackson. vol VII.p.43
  - Commission to Charles L[innaeus] Peale, Oct. 21, 1824; 7-3/4x12-1/2; Greek relief association
    Philadelphia, Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: W[illia]m T. Palmer. 1p.and end. vol VII p. 45
  - Receipt to Cha[rle]s L[innaeus] Peale, June 6, 1826; 5x6; Steward, James
    A.D.S. 1p. In pencil. vol VIIp.55
  - Receipt, June 7, 1826; 2-3/4x8; Boysen
    A.D.S. 1p. In Spanish.
  - Legal document, July 28, 1826; 13-1/2x8; Bernuth, N.
    D. 1p. In German. Seals. (see Peale papers.)
  - Passport to Charles L[inneaus] Peale, Aug. 11, 1826; 13-1/2x8-3/4; Colombia
    Cartegena, Printed D.filled in in ms. 1p.and end. vol VII p.58
  - Inventory of the personal property of Charles Wilson Peale (deceased) in the house in Walnut Street in the possession of Titian R. Peale, April 27, 1827; 10" x 8"; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    D.S: Chas. L. Peale, Franklin Peale 2p.
  - Will, June 5, 1827; 12-1/2x7-3/4; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    D. 7p.and end.
  - Stock issued to Rembrandt Peale, July 1, 1827; 8-1/2x7-3/4; Peale's Museum (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: Franklin Peale. Cancelled Oct. 28, 1828. 1p. (see Peale family papers.)
  - Transfer of stock to Franklin Peale in trust for Elizabeth Patterson, July 7, 1827; 4-1/4x6-1/4; Peale's Museum (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Franklin Peale,manager, Rem. Peale, Rubens Peale, Chas.L.Peale, Franklin Peale and T.R. Peale. 1p. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.)
  - Accounts to Charles Peale, July 27, 1827; Page, Rufus
  - Receipt to Coleman Sellers, executor for Ann Wood, Sept. 27-29, 1827; 5-1/4x7-3/4; Bunting, John, 1756-1832
  - Will, Oct. 13, 1827; 9x7-3/4; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    A.D. 1p. Inc. Concerning his wife and his estate.
  - Resolution to oppose J. Andrew Shulze for governor since he is anti-Jackson, [ca. 1827]; Unidentified
  - Indenture for the Philadelphia Arcade and the Philadelphia Museum Company, Jan.1, 1828; 13-1/4x8; Browne, Peter A. (Peter Arrell), 1782-1860
    D. 2p. Draft.
  - Receipt to Peter Hill, Jan. 1, 1828; 2-1/2x6; Rugan, John
    Printed D.S. 1p., end. For water rent.
  - Bank check to C. L. Peale, March 7, 1828; Sellers, Coleman, 1781-1834
    Schuylkill Bank check for one hundred sixty dollars.
  - Bill of sale for lot in burial ground, to Daniel Harrington, Sept. 9, 1828; 9-3/4x8; Philadelphia. First New Jerusalem Church
    D. 2p. Seals. ----Copy.
  - Concerning transfers of stock to various persons, Oct. 4 - Nov. 17, 1828; 7-1/2x6-1/4; Peale's Museum (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    D.S.: Franklin Peale, etc. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers correspondence.)
  - Bill of sale to Rubens Peale for the Peale's Museum of Baltimore, Oct. 31, 1828; 13x7-3/4; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
    Baltimore, Printed D.filled in in ms.S. 1p.and end. (see Peale papers.)
  - Ordinance for altering and improving the fish market, Nov. 27, 1829; 10x8; Philadelphia. Common council
    D. 1p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers collection.)
  - Receipts ..., 1828 - 1857; Unidentified
    Various receipts and accounts.
  - Accounts with Samuel Sellers, 1829-1837; 7-3/4x6-1/4; Second New Jerusalem Church of Philadelphia
    Treasurer of the Building Committee; D. 1vol.containing 36p.of which 10 contain writing. Presented by C.C.Sellers; Oct. 11, 1966.
  - Receipt for shipment to Franklin [Peale], May 25, 1830; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    New York, D.S.: Reuben Snow. 1p. (see Peale family papers.)
  - Petition to the Select and Common Council for the improvement of Washington Square, [ca. 1830?]; 30x10; Philadelphia. Citizens
    D.S. by 97 persons. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Lease of Lenni Farm to Daniel Lammot, May 1, 1831; 12-1/2x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, 1781-1834
    D.S.: Coleman Sellers and Daniel Lammot. 5p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Coleman Sellers acting as trustee for Hannah Sellers Hill.
    Note from previous folder: 'Lease of Lenni Farm' to be 'Lease of Lenni Cotton Factory,' according to David Dasserman (7/5/72).
  - Will, Nov. 1, 1831; 12-1/2x7-3/4, 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Elizabeth Coleman, 1751-1832
    D. 3p. Copy. ----Copy. 3p.and end.
  - Receipt to Peter Hill for medical bill, Dec. 31, 1831; 4x4-3/4; Moore, John
    Philadelphia, Printed D.filled in in ms.S. 1p.and add.
  - Receipt to John Bohlen for a power of attorney, May 12, 1832; 4-1/2x7-3/4; Biddle, Clement C. (Clement Cornell), 1784-1855
    D.S. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Agreement concerning paper-making machinery, between Coleman Sellers & Sons and Richard Ibbotson, Nov. 28, 1832; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Sellers, George Escol
    Draft of D. 4p.,end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Account with John Sellers, Nov. 3, 1832 - March 11, 1834; 7-1/2x8-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, 1781-1834
  - Report to the Board of Trustees of the Philadelphia Museum, Feb. 12, 1833; Peale, Franklin, 1795-1870
    3p. and add.
  - Passport issued to Franklin Peale, April 7, 1833; 17x10-1/2; U. S. Dept. of State
    Washington, Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: Franklin Peale, et al. 4p. (see Peale Papers. Mills collection.)
  - Receipt to Peter Hill for medical attendance, June 18, 1833; 4-1/2x5-1/2; Moore, John
    Philadelphia, Engraved D.filled in in ms.S. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Insurance policy to Coleman Sellers, trustee of Mrs. Hannah S[ellers] Hill, Sept. 20, 1833; 16x10; Pennsylvania Fire Insurance Company
    Printed D.filled in in ms.S. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - List of donations, Oct. 10, 1833; 12-3/4x7-1/2; Peale's Museum (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    A.D.S.: Titian R. Peale. 2p.,end. (see Peale Papers. Mills collection.) Chiefly natural history.
  - Power of attorney to Titian R[amsay] Peale, June 30, 1834; 6x7-3/4; Stockton, Eliza Ferguson Peale, 1799-1876
    D.S. 1p.and add.: "Mrs. Sophonisba Sellers", end. (see Peale family papers.)
  - Letter appointing Charles Sellers her proxy for the Philadelphia Museum, Jan. 5, 1835; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p. Witnessed: Geo[rge] Escol Sellers. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Agreement to build paper machinery, Feb. 4, 1835; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, & Sons
    D. 1p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Petition for patent on improvement on steam locomotives, March, 1835; 13x8; Sellers, George Escol
    D. 3p.and end. Draft. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Minutes, Aug. 4, 1835; 10x7-3/4; Peale's Museum (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    D.S.: A.Harrold, Sec. 1p. Extract. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) C.W.Peale never wished the museum to leave Philadelphia.
  - Receipt to Geo[rge] Escol Sellers for transference of Philadelphia museum stock to James M. Broom, Dec. 9, 1835; 3-1/4x7-3/4; Patterson, Elizabeth D.
  - Certificate to Christiana Peale, Jan. 15, 1836; Philadelphia. Register of Wills.
  - Receipt to James Wilcox, Jan. 27, 1836; 5x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, & Sons
  - Letter to authority for George Escol Sellers for vote for them in the Philadelphia museum company, April 8, 10, 1836; 13x8; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    D.S.: Rubens Peale, Samuel A. Porter and James Peale. 1p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Bill of sale to [Mrs.] Martha [McGlathery] Peale, June 13, 1836; 9-3/4x8; Peale, Edmund, 1805-1851
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 3p. (see Peale-Sellers Papers.) Sale of household articles.
  - Receipt to Coleman Sellers & Sons, June 13, 1836; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Peale, Edmund, d. 1851
    D.S. Witnessed: Harvey L. Sellers and Robert Kemp. 1p.
  - Donations and deposit list of items to the museum, 1836; 8x7-3/4; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
  - Power of attorney to Franklin Peale, June 30, 1837; 6-1/2x7-3/4; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: Rubens Peale. Witnessed: J.L.M.Stevens. 1p.and end. (see Peale family papers.)
  - Transfer of Philadelphia museum stock to James Peale, Sr. for Sale, Jan. 17, 1839; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Peale, Martha McGlathery, 1775-1852
    D. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) On same sheet as: Edmund Peale to Mrs. Martha Peale; Jan. 8, 1839.
  - Order to pay Sellers & Davis, March 14, 1839; 3x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, & Sons
    Printed D.filled in in ms.S. 1p.
  - Shares of stock issued to Rubens Peale, May 14, 1839; 7-1/2x9-3/4; Peale's Museum (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Philadelphia, Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: Nathan Dunn, president and Jno.J. Smith, jr., treasurer. 1p.and end. (see Peale family papers.)
  - Note to Geo[rge] Grigg for $400.00, June 8, 1839; 12x7-3/4, 3x7; Sellers, Coleman, & Sons
    Philadelphia, Printed D.filled in in ms.S. 2p.and end.
  - Power of attorney for sale of stock in the Philadelphia museum company, Nov. 6, 1840; 12-3 / 4x8; Bristol, William
    D.S. 1p.and end. by Andrew Warner. (see Peale-Sellerspapers.)
  - Resolution concerning Charles and George Escol Sellers, Oct., 1841; 10x7-1/2; Upper Darby Institute
    A.D.S.: Daniel Rhoads. 1p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning the loss of the Sellers' as members.
  - Receipts, etc., 1841; Sellers, George Escol
    D. 9 items. Various sizes. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Bill to C[harles] W. Peale, July 23, 1842; 12-3/4x7-3/4; Schraeder, J. F.
    Flushing, D. 2p.and end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Natural history items.
  - Discharge of bankruptcy of Charles and George Escol Sellers, Jan. 31, 1843; 11x9; United States. District Court. (Ohio: Southern District)
    Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: W[illia]m Miner, Clerk. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Discharge to Peter Hill, Feb. 24, 1843; 8x12-1/2; United States. District Court (Pennsylvania)
    Philadelphia, Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: Fra[ncis] Hopkinson. 1p.and end. vol II p.71
  - List of directors elected, Feb. 7, 1844; Philadelphia Museum Company.
  - Statement pertaining to debt owed him by G. E. Sellers, Charles Sellers, and Charles Sonntag, June 12, 1844; 6-1/2x7-3/4; Lawrence, Josiah
    D. 1p.and end. "Coppy" (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Concerning the Second New Jerusalem Church of Philadelphia's deed executed by the late Mrs. Parnell Earle., March 13, 1845; Unidentified
  - Receipt to Coleman Sellers from the estate of Alfred Harrold, Oct. 23, 1845; 3x8; Randall, J. C.
    A.D.S. 1p.and end. vol.II p.89
  - Compromise with the estate of Samuel Sellers, 1845-1846; 7x7-1/2; New Jerusalem. Church of the. Second
    D. 1p.and end. (see Peale Papers.) Finances. Presented by C.C. Sellers; Feb. 16, 1967.
  - Liquidation contract of the company, Sept. 28, 1846; 12-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, & Sons
    D.S.: Cha[rle]s Sellers, et al. 2p. Copy. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Appointment of George E. Sellers as a delegate at a meeting in New York, Oct. 16, 1845; 10x8; Ohio Mechanics' Institute
    Cincinnati, D.S.: Jno. P. Foote, Pres. and John W. Applegate, Sec. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Marriage certificate for C.W.Peale and Harriet Friel Peale, Nov. 9, 1846; 10x8; Peale, C. W.
    D. 1p.and end. Mutilated. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.)
  - Receipt to Coleman Sellers, March 1, 1847; 5x7-1/2; Price, William
    Cincinnati, A.D.S. 1p.and end. vol III,p.5
  - Concerning Coleman Sellers' estate, [1847?]; 12x7-1/2; Sellers, George Escol
    D. 2p. Incomplete.
  - Power of attorney to Coleman Sellers, Sept. 19, 1848; 3-3/4x8; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
    Mill Bank, A.D.S. 1p.
  - Agreement with Geo[rge] Escol Sellers concerning the Panama Rail Road, Oct. 25, 1848; 11x8; Norris, William, 1802-1867
    New York, D.S.: William Norris and Geo[rge] Escol Sellers. 1p.,witnessed. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) On same sheet with: Copies of letters from Sellers to Adams;Oct.25,1848; and Adams to Sellers;Oct.25, 1848.
  - Receipt to Coleman Sellers, Jan. 18, 1849; 2-1/2x8; Ogden & Lee
    Cincinnati, D. 1p.and end. vol III p.26
  - Check to L. Worthington, May 24, 1849; 3x8-1/4; Sellers, Charles, 1806-1898
    Cincinnati, Printed D.filled in in ms.S.(signature mutilated). 1p.
  - Receipt to Coleman Sellers, July 2, 1849; 2-3/4x7-1/2; Price,
    Cincinnati, D. 1p.and end. vol III p. 29
  - Promissory note to Geo[rge] Escol Sellers, Jan. 7, 1850; 3-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Cincinnati, A.D.S. 1p.and end.
  - Receipt to C[oleman] Sellers, March 1, 1850; 3x7-1/2; Price,
    Cincinnati, D. 1p. and end. vol III, p.37
  - Receipt to C[oleman] Sellers, Sept. 8, 1850; 3-1/2x6-1/2; Ogden & Lee
    Cincinnati, D. 1p.and end. vol III. p. 37
  - Power of attorney to Coleman Sellers, Oct. 6, 1850; 3-1/2x7-3/4; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 1p.
  - Memorandum of agreement with the Panama Rail Road Company, Nov. 1, 1850; 13x8; Sellers, George Escol
    A.D. 1p.and end. Draft. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) For manufacture of locomotives.
  - Statement of accounts to the Panama Rail Road Company, Nov. 20, 1850; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Higham & Company
    New York, D. 1p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Deed of cemetery lot to his brother, Franklin, 1850; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    A.D.S.with initials. 1p. Draft. (see Peale papers. No.10.)
  - List of spikes ordered, [1850?]; 10x8; Panama Railroad Co.
    A.D. in hand of G.E.Sellers. 1p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Report on Kyan's process for preserving railway timbers, [1850?]; 13x8-1/4; Sellers, George Escol
    A.D. 2p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Receipt to C[oleman] Sellers, Feb., 1851; 6x3-1/2; Price, William R.
    Cincinnati, D.S. 1p.and add. vol III p.48
  - Receipt to C[oleman] Sellers, March 8, 1851; 4x6-1/4; Ogden & Lee
    Cincinnati, D. 1p. vol III p.65
  - Expenses, March 15, 1851; 4x8; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Receipt to C[oleman] Sellers, April 21, 1851; 3-1/2x6-1/4; Ogden & Lee
    Cincinnati, D. 1p. vol III p. 65
  - Accounts, July 9 - Nov. 23, 1851; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, George Escol
  - Promissory note to Diana Wells, Oct. 2, 1851; 4-1/2x8; Sellers, Cornelia Wells, 1831-1909
    Cincinnati, D.S.: Cornelia Wells and L.T.Wells. 1p.and end.
  - Extract of minutes, Dec., 1851; 12-1/2x7-1/2; New Jerusalem. Church of the. Second
    Philadelphia, D. 5p. (see Peale Papers.) Concerning debt to Samuel Sellers estate. Presented by C.C. Sellers; Feb. 16, 1967.
  - Receipt to George Escol Sellers, March 28, 1853; 6x6-1/2; Warren, George
    Cincinnati, D.S. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) For work on the locomotive.
  - Account with the Panama Rail Road Company, Dec., 1853; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, George Escol
    A.D. 1p.and end. (see Pealé-Sellers papers.)
  - Will, Aug. 11, 1854; 14-1/2x10; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    D.S. 7p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Indenture for land in Illinois, and letter to "Gentlemen", Nov., 1854
    Indenture for land granted to C. L. Peale, and sold (?) by daughter Alverda and son-in-law Isreal Amies; also: Letter to "Gentelman" discussing the museum.
  - Receipt to the treasurer of the U.S., Jan. 31, 1855; 6x8; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Cincinnati, D.S.with signature mutilated. 1p.and financial statement on back.
  - Agreement with Nathan Sellers Hill concerning mortgages on the estate of Mrs. Hannah Sellers Hill, Dec. 22, 1856; 12-1/2x8; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    D.S.: Ann Sellers, N[atha]n Sellers and Witnessed: Abn. L. Pennock. "Correct copy. N. Sellers Hill" 1p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Miscellaneous accounts, 1856; Sellers, George Escol
    Various receipts to G. E. Sellers. Also: two envelopes with pressed plants.
  - Agreement with Henry Huddleson to rent Lenni Farm, Jan. 1, 1857; 10x8, 13x8; Hill, Peter, d. 1857
    D.S.: Peter Hill, N.Sellers Hill, and Henry Huddleson.
  - Receipt to Coleman Sellers for medical services, Jan. 1, 1857; 4x8; Neidhard, C. (Charles), 1809-1895
    Philadelphia, Printed D.filled in in ms.S. 1p.and end. vol IVp.41
  - Receipt to Coleman Sellers, March 6, 1857; 3-3/4x5; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
  - Receipt to Coleman Sellers for purchase of flour, March 11, 1857; 4x7; Sellers, John
  - Receipt to Coleman Sellers for a monochrome drawing of Washington, June 9, 1857; 4x7; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 1p.and end. (see Peale papers.) This was originally in: Rembrandt Peale, Introduction to notes on the painting room...
  - Deposition concerning business arrangements with Charles W. Peale, Sept. 15, 1857; 12-1/2x8; Payne, William
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p.and end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.)
  - Will, Feb. 12, 1859; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Elizabeth Burd Patterson, 1795-1864
    D.S. 4p.and codicil of 2 paragraphs. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) ---Copy.
  - Announcement of sale of his painting, Feb. 22, 1859; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
    1p. announcement of paintings being shown in "lower room of my dwelling".
  - Will, April 26, 1858; 13x8; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    D.S. 5p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Bond to Coleman Sellers, April 20, 1859; 10x7-1/2; Van Horn, Israel
    Philadelphia, D.S. 2p.and end. vol. IV p. 50
  - Receipt to Coleman Sellers, June 29, 1859; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Bonsall Bros.
    D. 1p.and end. vol IVp.50
  - Patent to John Henry Johnson, Aug. 30, 1859; 12-3/4x8; Great Britain. Office of the commissioners of patents
    Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: L. Edmunds. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Patent for steam generators.
  - Will, Oct. 17, 1859; 12-1/4x8; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    D. 2p.and end.and affadavit for registering will.
  - Receipt to the estate of Sophonisba Peale Sellers, Oct. 27, 1859; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Moore, William Hill
    Philadelphia, D. 1p.and end. Burial expenses. vol IVp52
  - Statement of funds belonging to the estate of Coleman Sellers, April, 1860; 12-1/2x8; Smith, Aubrey H., ca. 1813-1891
    D. 3p.and end. vol IV p. 52
  - Inventory of furniture, Nov., 1859; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola. Estate.
  - Petition to the U.S. commissioner of patents, Sept. 27, 1861; 12-3/4x8-1/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Philadelphia, D. 5p.and end. Application for patent for projectile for army. vol IV p.58
  - Statement as to the facts in Illinois against J[ohn] M. Woodward, [1861?]; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, George Escol
    A.D. 2p. Draft. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Settlement of debts.
  - Receipt book, Oct. 15, 1862 -Feb. 15, 1867; 6-3/4x4; Peale, C. W.
    D. 12 leaves. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.)
  - Pass for Coleman Sellers to photograph railroad bridge, Oct. 15, 1862; 5-1/2x7-3/4; Sharpless, J. C.
  - Receipt to Coleman Sellers, Dec. 15, 1862; 7 x 8-1/2; Philadelphia. Collector of taxes.
    Philadelphia, Printed D. filled in in ms. 1p. vol IV p. 60
  - Presidential Appointment, Brigade Surgeon of Volunteers, 1862; United States. President.
  - Affadavit for patent on a new method of preparing paper stock, 1863; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, George Escol
  - Certification that Coleman Sellers has paid for draftee, April 4, 1864; 7-3/4x11; Philadelphia. Ward 15
    Printed D. filled in in ms.S.: W[illa]m Matthews, treas'r and J. Atlee White. 1p. Mutilated. vol IV p.64
  - Receipt to Coleman Sellers, March 31, 1866; 8x4-3/4; McIlvain, John H.
    A.D.S. 1p.and add.,end. Vol. IV p.71
  - Tuition bill for Coleman Sellers, June 5, 1866; 8x5; Gregory, I. N.
    A.D.S. 1p. Vol IV,p 70
  - Receipt to C. W. Peale, Dec. 30, 1865; 14x8-1/2; Mann, William, 1814-1881
    D. 1p. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.)